Guide to the International Congress of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences Records 1970-1984
University of Chicago Library
International Congress of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences. Records
1970-1984
73.5 linear feet (142 boxes)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
The ICAES Records consist of the preparation materials and scholastic work for the conference held in Chicago in 1973. The correspondence consists of letters between Sol Tax and his secretaries to the conference participants and between the editors and writers of the papers that were presented and published. The materials also included the mock up materials and the final packet for the conference participants, as well as press releases and final drafts of the presentation papers. Conference participants included well known intellectuals such as Margaret Mead, Prince Peter of Greece and Denmark, L. Lomnitz, James Fernandez, Marshall Sahlins, McKim Marriott, June Nash, and Alan Lomax.
Information on Use
Access
Series XI contains personnel and financial material to which access is restricted until 2025. The remainder of the collection is open for research.
Historical Note
The International Congress of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences has met regularly around the world since the second World War. The Ninth Congress, held under the leadership of Professor Sol Tax in Chicago in 1973, hosted 4,000 scholars from more than 100 countries. In addition to the scholarly panels, the University of Chicago hosted the Youth for Mankind conference for high school students and cultural programs such an ethnographic opera by Gian Carlo Menotti and the American Folk Concert organized by Alan Lomax.
Scope Note
Series I: Administrative Records, include membership and registration lists in addition to information on permanent council meetings, panel topics, grants, travel and hotel arrangements, translators, and preparations for future conferences.
Series II: Correspondence, includes abstracts for papers, papers, orders for papers, registrations and general correspondence.
Series III: Materials for conference packets, includes drafts, letters, and mock ups for brochures, posters and publicity. The completed conference packet is also included.
Series IV contains research materials and information on other anthropological conferences.
Series V: Cultural Programs includes materials about the opera, Tamu Tamu by Gian Carlo Menotti, and the American Folk Concert arranged by Alan Lomax specifically for the conference.
Series VI: Youth for Mankind, contains correspondence, organizational and publicity materials for the conference for high school students in the summer of 1973.
Series VII: contains photographs of the conference participants and press releases.
Series VIII contains materials regarding publication of conference materials and proceedings, including correspondence from publishers, editors and authors, abstracts, conference papers, original drafts and the Proceeding for World Anthropology Publications.
Series IX contains posters, press materials and charts.
Series X contains reel to real tapes, cassette tapes and cds of recorded conference panels.
Series XI contains personnel and financial material to which access is restricted for fifty years.
Related Resources
Browse finding aids by topic.
Subject Headings
Tax, Sol, 1907-; International Congress of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences; Anthropology; Ethnography
INVENTORY
- Series I: Administrative Records
  - Subseries 1: Mailing, Membership, and Registration lists
    - Mailing list, completed additions, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - List of members, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Corrections to mailing lists, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Mailing lists to Ford and Asia foundations, Dept. of Anthropology., undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Mailing list, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Participant list, membership, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - American Canadian mailing list, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Youth for Mankind mailing list, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Editors' mailing list, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Mailing list, membership list for, "consultation on Ethnicity in Education," second circular, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Mailing labels, C.A. directory, Institutional Assoc. from 1969 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Foreign registrants mailing list except Yugoslavia, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Official delegates from institutions, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Hirschfield, membership list, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Computer print out membership list, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - IUAES/ICAES, membership lists, publishers correspondence with editors, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Cancelled memberships, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Paid, no file membership, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - People, general file, 1971-1975 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - People, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Registration by country, ICAES, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Congress member lists, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Registration statistics, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Third circular reply, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Third circular reply, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Third circular reply form, Proceedings, Ted Cloak correspondence, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Form D, registration fees, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - New registration and changes of address, fall 1974 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - List of congress registrants, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Mailing list of third world participants, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Registered Foreign Students, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Southeast Asia, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Oceania, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Eastern Europe, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - East Asia, Mongolia, Taiwan, Korea, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Africa, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - North Africa, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Western Europe, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Cuba, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Czechoslovakia, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - South Asia, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - China, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Japan (Nakane correspondence), 1972 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - South and Central America, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - U.S.S.R. (Bromley correspondence), 1973-1975 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Registration lists-Russian, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Membership list, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Subseries 2: Foreign Students, registration forms
    - Registration forms, A, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Registration forms, B, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Registration forms, C, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Registration forms, D, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Registration forms, E, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Registration forms, G, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Registration forms, H, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Registration forms, I-J, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Registration forms, K, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Registration forms, L, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Registration forms, M, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Registration forms, N, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Registration forms, O, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Registration forms, P-Q, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Registration forms, R, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Registration forms, S, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Registration forms, T, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Registration forms, U-V, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Registration forms, W, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Registration forms, X,Y,Z, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Notes, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Student registration forms, A, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Student registration forms, B, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Student registration forms, C, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Student registration forms, D, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Student registration forms, E, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Student registration forms, F, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Student registration forms, G, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Student registration forms, H, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Student registration forms, I, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Student registration forms, J, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Student registration forms, K, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Student registration forms, L, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Student registration forms, M, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Student registration forms, N, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Student registration forms, O, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Student registration forms, P, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Student registration forms, Q, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Student registration forms, R, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Student registration forms, S, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Student registration forms, T, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Student registration forms, U, V, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Student registration forms, W, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Student registration forms, X, Y, Z, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Europe, registration and abstracts, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - The Indian Ocean areas, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 3: Card files
    - Index cards for foreign registrants, undated (Box 8)
    - Index cards for Associates Registration for ICAES, undated (Box 9)
    - Index cards, registrations (Box 10)
    - Index cards, Original registrations, undated (Box 11)
    - Microfilm, undated (Box 11)
    - Index cards with addresses for Youth for Mankind registrations and student volunteers, undated (Box 12)
    - Registration index cards, 1973 (Box 13)
    - Index cards, registration cards, addresses (Box 14)
    - Rubber Stamps (Box 14)
  - Subseries 4: Permanent Council
    - IUAES Commissions, Reports and Resolutions, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Union and Congress Membership lists, Money for people to come, Commerce Dept., Break down of people, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Permanent Council Meeting including F. Barth, Copenhagen, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - IUAES statutes, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - IUAES, 1964-1965 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Financial, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - University of Chicago, letter to Edward H. Levi, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Financial memos, post-congress, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Sample form, C, $25.00 letter form, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - membership list, undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - List for emergency fund, travel, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Registration, material related to, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Membership fees, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - American Council of Learned Societies-Copenhagen travel grant correspondence, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - NEH, introduction, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Corporation accounts, Werner-Gren science conference program, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Budget, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Registration fee, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Membership lists, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Grants, information and question are, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - AAA, letter to departments, addenda, 1,2,3, undated (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Lists of conference members, grant applications, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Budget, Sept 1973 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Budget, 1972-1973 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Funding II, undated (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Report of the Secretary general, 1970-1 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - "Sundry dope" on sessions, organizers, correspondence with Ted Cloak, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - History of scheduling, June 1973 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Index cards, ideas for panels, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Preparation for Proceedings, 1972-1973 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Membership list paid, undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Membership checks received, undated (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Money book, undated (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Membership, hotel list, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Log of long distance calls, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Mail log, paper orders, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Proposal to Permanent Council, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Poland at the 9th congress, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - D Plenary Sessions, general information, speakers, IUAES, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - IUAES after Tokyo, (Kraeder-Tax), 1968 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - IUAES and International congress, Sol Tax's notes, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Permanent Council, Belshaw, Kraeder, 1971-1976 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Congress, Tokyo, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - IUAES, NRC Committees, Kraeder-Tax, before Tokyo congress, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - ISSC Meeting Paris, June 1974 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - UNESCO, US National Commission for UNESCO, 1974 ICOM-UNESCO, 1972 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Americanist congress-Rome, Sept. 1972 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Permanent Council, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Archeo-Astronomy, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - The Atlantic, 1972 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 5: Panel Topics
    - Linguistics, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Man and the Primates, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Nature and the development of man (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Paleoanthropology: The Pleistocene, abstracts, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Plan of Program Development, undated (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Ritual, Cults and Shamanism, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Session numbers for scholarly sessions and activities, undated (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Salvage archaeology, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 6: Grants
    - National Endowment for Humanities, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Development Office, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Department of Commerce, grants, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Agricultural development council, 1972 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - American Anthropological Association, 1971 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - American Anthropological Association, 1971-1972 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Asian Foundation, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - CIPSH (D'ormesson), 1976 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Feldstein and Company, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Ford Foundation, general grant, 1973-1974 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Ford Foundation/Fuchs, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Ford Foundation, Bangladesh, 1973-1974 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Fromm Music Foundation, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - IREX, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Institution of International Education, 1973 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Institutional Sponsors, 1971 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - National Research Council, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - National Science Foundation, 1972-1976 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - National Science Foundations, printed material only, undated (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Russell Sage Foundation, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - State Department and Percy Stevenson, 1973 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - UNESCO, 1973 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Werner Gren, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Copies of bills and invoices, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Invoices, 1972-1975 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 7: Travel Arrangements
    - Charters, 1973 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Capitol International Airways, London Charter cancelled, 1973 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Paris Charter Correspondence with C. Bouloux, 1973 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Charter information, 1973 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Other travel agencies, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Other travel agencies, 1973 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Originals, travel and registration packets, 1973 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Travel, undated (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Transport, 1973 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Returned charter forms from participants, 1973-1975 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Returned charter forms from participants, 1973-1975 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Conrad Hilton Hotel, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Information sent to Hilton, rooms and bills, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Conrad Hilton, bill and analysis, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - "4" Hotel, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Other hotels, (not Conrad Hilton), 1972 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Hotel suites, 1972-1973 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Special requests for space and equipment, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Auditorium, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Meeting rooms, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Hotel contracts, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Regional-Conrad Hilton, Nov 1971 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Planning Meeting, Conrad Hilton, rooms for members, Chicago, March 1973 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Center for Continuing Education, Guest Room Rates, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Lists sent to the Hilton, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Subseries 8: Translators
    - Simultaneous translation, tape transcripts, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Equipment and Systems, taping and recording of congress, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Translator contracts, undated (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Tapes Listing, undated (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Translation equipment, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Simultaneous translation, interpretation services, 1971-1977 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 9: Future Conferences
    - Future congresses, location advertising, Las Vegas and Israel, 1975 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Future congresses, location advertising, Hawaii, 1971, 1975 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Future congresses, location advertising, 1975 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 10: General Materials
    - A, 1972 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Acceptance letters, (forms), 1973 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Advertisements, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Appointment calendar with notes, 1970-1971 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Bibliography conference, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Books, inventories, sales reports, general, undated (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Budget for Chicago Metro Film Project, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Catalogue of papers-supplement, 1973 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Charts, 1973 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Chicago Convention, 1973 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Chicago Guide, 1973 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - First circular, July 1971 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Second Circular, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Third Circular, 1973 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Computerization, 1973 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Computerization, 1973 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Conference paperwork, 1973 (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Congress and Union, changed dates, correspondence with Sol Tax, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Countries and population, circa 1973 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Countries and population, 1972 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Countries and population, 1972 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Current Anthropology History, 1957 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Drafts and correspondence, 1972 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Drafts and correspondence, circa 1973 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Drafts and correspondence, 1973 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Draft of form letters and old notes, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Draft of form letters and old notes, 1975 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Ebony, 1974 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Finance Committee report, 1977 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - French translation of IUAES constitution, 1977 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - General research materials, 1974 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Geographic Distribution, 1973-1975 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Geographic Distribution Registration, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Geographic Distribution materials, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Good ideas which never happened, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Historical Development of Papers Categories, 1971 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Developing Papers, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Developing Papers, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Paperwork, drafts, 1973 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Paperwork, drafts, 1973 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Program, 1973 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Index cards, circa 1973 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Various notes, circa 1973 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Various materials, including correspondence, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Keyword index, 1972 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Insurance, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Invitations, 1972 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - IRC, circa 1973 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - IUAES, calendar, 1971-1974 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - IUAES, Research and Development Projects Committee, 1977 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Form letter originals, 1973-1974 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Form letter originals for duplication, 1971 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Form letters, copies, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Letters to participants to be drafted, notes, 1972 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Master file-letters to participants, circa 1973 (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Master file, letters, 1971-1972 (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Materials on more than 600 local resources including the Chicago Public Library, 1972 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Local sites information, Illinois Department of Business, undated (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Manuscript Reply, reassign or other problems, 1973 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Mass copied preparation materials, 1973 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - D.N. Mjumdar commemorative vol., 1978 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Money to come, budget revisions, 1972 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Money to come, sources, 1973 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Mouton catalogs, 1973 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Pamphlets from Mouton publishers, 1973 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Gay Neuberger, 1977 (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Gay Neuberger, notes, plenary sessions, 1972 (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Notes for book, 1973 (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - Notes, 1973 (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - Notes to new secretary, file index, 1974-1977 (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - Old notes, 1973 (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - Notes, 1973-1978 (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - Notes, 1973-1979 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Office procedures, 1974 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Original forms, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Originals form letters, reports, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Organizing members, 1975 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Papers, 1978 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Out of the conference, 1973-1972 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Papers list, 1974 (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - List of papers not in catalog, undated (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Papers released, 1975 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Planning conference, stage II, Oct 1972 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Closing plenary session, 1978 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - People to help, congress service corps, 1973 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - People to help, Chicago staff, 1973 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - People to help, outside people, circa 1973 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Pre-conference, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Pre-congress conference letter, list information, circa 1973 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Preface-Sol Tax and Gay Neuberger, 1977 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Printing corporations, 1973 (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Printing and publication, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Proposed Paper, registrations, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Randy's summaries, Kelly, 1978 (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Reports to Sol Tax, office procedure, mailings, circa 1973 (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - Reviews from clip service, 1973 (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - Reviews, bibliography, 1973 (Box 35, Folder 16)
    - Congressional record, 1973 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - State of analyses of contents of volume summaries, 1974 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Statistical counts, undated (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Stationary, undated (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Sol Tax, drafts and the first revisions of the World Anthropology prefaces (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Tax, Sol, notes, undated (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Tax, Sol, notes, 1974 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Tax, Sol, Originals and drafts, 1977 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Tax, Sol, Originals and drafts, undated (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - USA delegation in Rome, 1976 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Visits and metro project, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - West Africa, French volume, "Subsistence and economic systems, 1978 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Withdrawals from congress service corps, 1973 (Box 37, Folder 2)
- Series II: Correspondence, Papers and Registration Materials
  - Address, A, 1973 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Congress Service Corps, A, 1973 (Box 37, Folder 4)